Ankit Bhatia

Profile

14 years experienced passionate developer with proven technical and organizational skills seeking a challenging position in your organization.

With strong analytical, coding, leadership and problem solving expertise, I look forward to scale my career in Tech Leadership roles.

Employment History

Senior Frontend Developer - II, Novorise Fintech Pvt Ltd, Gurugram

09/2021 - Present

- Company's revenue increased by \$200,000 in the first month of launch, with Express ACH feature built by me in core banking division.
- Enabled small business by developing Novo Funding feature, where Novo, in first 6months, had loaned approx 10million USD to its end users.
- Lead the frontend development of Debit card feature including user facing application as well as Novo Administrator portal, which is generating 60% of the revenue for novo and is the most critical core banking feature for the organization.
- Outside project I am leading the team responsible for JS to TS migration, and, identifying security vulnerabilities in the web apps and fixing them.

Frontend Lead, Epsilon Conversant, Bengaluru

12/2019 - 09/2021

- Mentored & Lead multiple teams of 5-7 developers each.
- Reduced the overall development time by building processes for frontend team and aligned the development process in sync with AEM.
- Brought impact in Digital Division by developing internal tools for sales & management dept. using MERN Stack, which were later showcased to bid for external projects.
- I was the representative for and acted as a link between the frontend team and the client

Technical Lead, TEKSystems, Bengaluru

05/2019 - 12/2019

- Lead & mentored a team of 3 developers.
- Had to communicate with client directly for the status updates, work progress and project estimations and timelines.
- Established code reviews process and helped reducing technical debt by 30%

Sr. Interactive Developer, Sapient Consulting, Gurugram

02/2014 - 05/2019

- Built the web apps for MFS and Fidelity UK from scratch.
- Demonstrated efficient use of Agile which got recognized at client side.
- Helped increase overall traffic by developing new features in Personal Investor division.
- Single-handedly worked on creating the components in AEM while working on the MFS webapp.

Lead Engineer, HCL Technologies, Noida

Personal Details

A-1/75, Sector - 5, Rohini Delhi, 110085 India +91 999 040 6652 ankit.bhatia87@gmail.com

Courses

Practical GitHub Copilot, **LinkedIn Learning**

The Ultimate Photography **Course in Post-Processing** & Editing. **Udemy**

Learning Node.js, **Linkedin Learning**

TypeScript: Object-Oriented Programming, **LinkedIn Learning**

Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bha-

https://github.com/ankitbhatia87

Skills

HTML5 CSS 3 **Javascript** ReactJS Redux NodeJS

SCSS, LESS, Tailwind

04/2011 - 01/2014

- Singlehandedly managed the frontend of client's web app with 100% billability.
- Introduced jQuery in the projects for building advanced features and better animations in the app.
- Developed plugins like accordion, image carousels, floating popups, infinity tabs, etc. using jQuery.

Software Development Engineer, Treystaa Services, Delhi

08/2009 - 12/2010

- Brought a significant value add to the product by building the reports feature in it using jQuery and actionscript 3.
- Helped product owners in creating interactive video demos using actionscript 3 for marketing and promotional activities in Adobe Flash.

Web Designer, Vinove Software & Services, Delhi

07/2008 - 07/2009

- I was able to convert 3-4 PSDs in 1 day apparantly increasing the revenue of the company
- Trained junior web designers in developing the webpages from scratch using XHTML, CSS and javascript.
- Later I took charge of the frontend for invoicing and money management products and scaled them from PoCs to revenue generation products.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, Sikkim Manipal University

08/2004 - 01/2008

Extra Curricular Activities

Volunteer, Sameer Foundation, Delhi

04/2013 - 02/2018

- Volunteer for teaching under privileged students. Taught basics of computer.
- Administrative volunteer to organize trips to historical places for under privileged students. Took them to places like Taj Mahal, Doll Museum, Rail Museum, Qutub Minar etc.

Grunt, Gulp, Webpack

RESTApi, GraphQL

MongoDb, Postgres

Agile (Scrum)

Hobbies

Photography, History, Geopolitics and Reading